

Ph.D. Student at Georgia Tech

RESEARCH INTERESTS

NATURAL LANGUAGE PROCESSING (NLP)

The long-term goal of my research is to enhance the *practicality* of NLP systems (e.g., Large Language Models) so that they can be widely used in real-world scenarios. In particular, my research focuses on i) how to make NLP models cheaper (i.e., efficient) in terms of data, parameters, or compute, and ii) how to build NLP models that are robust to unseen cases in the wild.

EDUCATION

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Research Assistant at NLP X Lab (Advisors: Dr. Alan Ritter, Dr. Wei Xu)

Atlanta, GA, USA Aug. 2022 - Present

KOREA ADVANCED INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY (KAIST)

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Research Assistant at IR&NLP Lab (Advisor: Dr. Sung-Hyon Myaeng)
- Thesis committee: Dr. Sung-Hyong Myaeng, Dr. Hojin Choi, Dr. Alice Oh
- GPA: 4.03 / 4.30

CHUNGNAM NATIONAL UNIVERSITY

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

- · Summa Cum Laude
- GPA: 4.30 / 4.50 (Rank: 1/125 in CSE, Major GPA: 4.41)

Daejeon, Republic of Korea Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2019

Daejeon, Republic of Korea

Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2021

PUBLICATIONS

[1] Distill or Annotate? Cost-Efficient Fine-Tuning of Compact Models Junmo Kang, Wei Xu, Alan Ritter

ACL 2023

[2] Graph-Induced Transformers for Efficient Multi-Hop Question Answering Giwon Hong, Jeonghwan Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

EMNLP 2022

- [3] Exploiting Numerical-Contextual Knowledge to Improve Numerical Reasoning in Question Answering Findings of NAACL 2022 Jeonghwan Kim, **Junmo Kang**, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [4] Ultra-High Dimensional Sparse Representations with Binarization for Efficient Text Retrieval **EMNLP 2021** Kyoung-Rok Jang, Junmo Kang, Giwon Hong, Sung-Hyon Myaeng, Joohee Park, Taewon Yoon, Heecheol Seo [pdf]
- [5] Leveraging Order-Free Tag Relations for Context-Aware Recommendation **EMNLP 2021** Junmo Kang, Jeonghwan Kim, Suwon Shin, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]
- [6] Have You Seen That Number? Investigating Extrapolation in Question Answering Models **EMNLP 2021** Jeonghwan Kim, Giwon Hong, Kyung-min Kim, Junmo Kang, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

May 2, 2023 Junmo Kang - CV 1/2 [7] Can You Distinguish Truthful from Fake Reviews? User Analysis and Assistance Tool for Fake Review Detection

HCI+NLP@EACL 2021

Jeonghwan Kim*, Junmo Kang*, Suwon Shin*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

[8] Regularization of Distinct Strategies for Unsupervised Question Generation Junmo Kang*, Giwon Hong*, Haritz Puerto San Roman*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

Findings of EMNLP 2020

[9] Handling Anomalies of Synthetic Questions in Unsupervised Question Answering Giwon Hong*, Junmo Kang*, Doyeon Lim*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

COLING 2020

[10] Let Me Know What to Ask: Interrogative-Word-Aware Question Generation Junmo Kang*, Haritz Puerto San Roman*, Sung-Hyon Myaeng [pdf]

MRQA@EMNLP 2019

EXPERIENCES

MIT-IBM WATSON AI LAB

May. 2023 - Aug. 2023 (Expected)

RESEARCH INTERN

· Working on large language models.

GEORGIA TECH NLP X LAB

Aug. 2022 - Present

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Worked on cost-efficiency analysis of small and large language models [1].

KAIST IR&NLP LAB Mar. 2021 - Jul. 2022

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

· Worked on efficient methods for multi-hop QA [2].

KAIST IR&NLP Lab Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2021

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Worked on question generation and unsupervised question answering for data-efficiency [8,9,10].
- Presented sample-efficient and robust number representations for question answering [6,3].
- Proposed a novel generation model that takes into account the inter-dependency of tags while alleviating the order sensitivity [5].
- Proposed a novel sparse representation model for passage retrieval that can take advantage of an efficient inverted index and symbolic IR techniques [4].

REPUBLIC OF KOREA ARMY

Apr. 2013 - Jan. 2015

HONORABLY DISCHARGED AS SERGEANT

· Compulsory military service.

HONORS & AWARDS

Graduated with Highest Honor in CSE, Chungnam National University	2019
Grand Prize, Business ICT Competition	2018
Excellence Award, Startup Competition	2018
Finalist, NAVER AI Hackathon	2018
Grand Prize, Daejeon Startup School	2017
Best Excellence Award, Startup Picnic	2016
Finalist, Microsoft Imagine Cup Korea	2016

^{*} indicates equal contribution.